What is it?
怎麼了？
A pig.
豬豬
It's a souvenir from Chile.
智利的伴手禮
It's a talisman from that region.
是那裡的護身符
I see. A talisman.
這樣啊，護身符
What kind of talisman?
什麼樣的護身符？
I want you guys to know that I didn't buy them.
我先說那不是我買的
My mom sent them to me.
是我媽寄給我的
So what kind of talisman is it?
所以到底是什麼護身符？
For family safety?
保佑全家平安？
No, not that.
不是
Safe birth!
安全生產
Why "safe birth"? That's ridiculous.
為什麼要保佑“安全生產”？ 太荒謬了吧
Then what's it for?
那是什麼呢？
Friendship…
守護友情…
Friendship?
友情啊？
Yes, it's something like that, I think.
差不多就是那樣
Thank you. I'll treasure it.
謝謝，我會好好珍惜的
Friendship?
友情啊？
I guess this means that we're friends forever.
這代表我們永遠都是朋友
I'm overjoyed!
好開心
I'm not sure it means "forever."
我不確定是不是“永遠”的意思
It means we'll never be able to separate.
代表我們這輩子都不可能分開了
-No. -Pervert!
-沒這回事 -變態
I didn't buy them!
又不是我買的
My mom sent them to me.
我媽寄給我的
I'm stuck to you!
我黏在你身上了
Good morning!
早安喔
Ready, set, good!
預備，就位，出發
Nice to be here!
請多多指教
Morning!
早安
As usual,
一如往常
everyone else in class continued to ignore me.
班上的人繼續排擠我
But that didn't matter much to me.
我覺得那倒無所謂
What's that?
那是什麼？
Did you buy that?
是妳買的嗎？
It was a gift?
別人送的？
Is that right? How cute.
是嗎？好可愛
But as for Aoi…
但是，對於蒼井…
I plan on plunging Kotani into such deep despair
我打算讓小谷陷入絕望
that she wants to kill herself.
讓她想自殺
When I see her, I'm overcome with such a feeling of horror,
我看著她的時候，心中充滿了恐懼
I can hardly breathe.
讓我快不能呼吸了
Shuji!
哥
Your friend is here.
你的朋友來了
My friend?
我的朋友？
Hey!
回來啦
Welcome home.
歡迎回來
-Thank you so much for doing this. -No problem.
-很感謝妳幫忙做菜 -別客氣
What are you doing?
妳在做什麼？
My hamburger steak is really delicious.
我做的漢堡排很好吃喔
What the heck are you doing here?
妳在這裡做什麼？
I promised that I'd show you the photos, right?
我答應過要拿照片給你看，不是嗎？
Oh, what's that? It's so cute!
那是什麼？好可愛
We've got an extra one. Have it.
我們多了一隻，給妳吧
-Really? -What are you doing?
-真的嗎？ -你在做什麼？
-Thank you! -She can have it.
-謝謝 -就給她啊
This looks delicious!
看起來好好吃
Don't touch it!
別碰
We haven't said our thanks yet.
我們還沒說開動呢
Oops. My bad habit.
對了，我的壞習慣
Actually, I'll be going.
我要走了
-Really? -I've got cram school.
-是嗎？ -我得去補習
-You should stay and eat with us. -Yes.
-妳應該跟我們一起吃的 -對啊
Kiritani, here are the photos I promised.
桐谷，這是我答應要給你的照片
See you tomorrow at school.
明天學校見
Good night.
打擾了
Thank you so much.
謝謝妳啊
-Goodbye. -Bye.
-再見
-Bye-bye. -Take care.
-慢走
-What? -What are you doing?
-什麼？ -你在做什麼？
Why are you doing that?
你為什麼要這麼做？
What's the matter? What?
怎麼了？什麼？
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
You're kidding!
怎麼搞的？
Why did you do that?
你為什麼要這麼做？
After she went to the trouble of making it, why would you do that?
她特地煮給我們吃，為何要倒掉？
What'll we do for dinner now?
那晚餐要怎麼辦？
I'll buy us something.
我去買給你們吃
This wasn't simply hatred.
這不是討厭一個人那麼單純
This was more like…
反倒像是…
Hey!
喂
What the heck are you doing?
妳到底在做什麼？
I want to be one of you guys.
我想加入你們
One of us?
加入我們？
It doesn't have to be forever.
我們不必當一輩子的朋友
Just let me be one of the people producing Nobuta.
讓我一起改造野豬吧
Then just like you asked,
然後我就照你說的
I'll disappear from Kotani's life without a word.
我會二話不說從小谷的生活中消失
Since I had no idea what she was thinking,
我完全摸不透她在想什麼
I was afraid.
好可怕
Good morning!
早安
Kotani!
小谷
-Good morning. -Look at this.
-早安 -聽我說
Voilà!
妳看
Kiritani and I made up.
我跟桐谷已經和好了
Also, he asked me if I would help be a producer for you.
他還問我要不要一起改造妳
Is that all right if I join you guys?
我可以加入你們嗎？
You mean, everything that happened until now was done by Aoi?
也就是說，到目前為止發生的事 都是蒼井做的？
That's right.
沒錯
What did she do it for?
她為什麼要這麼做？
I have no idea.
我也不知道
I see.
這樣啊
Aoi?
是蒼井啊？
That hurts!
好痛
Anyway, sit down.
先坐下吧
I see…
這樣啊…
-I'll kick her ass! -What?
-我去揍扁她 -什麼？
Hey! Wait!
喂，等等
-Wait! -Let go of me!
-等等 -放開我
You can't hit a woman!
不能打女生啊
Oh, yeah! That's right! I forgot that!
對喔，我都忘了
Okay?
對吧？
But isn't Aoi, Nobuta's friend?
但蒼井不是野豬的朋友嗎？
That's right.
沒錯
Also…
還有…
She wants to join our group.
她想加入我們
Join our group? You mean me, you, and Nobuta?
加入我們？ 你是指我、你，還有野豬？
-Yes. -What?
-對 -什麼？
Absolutely not!
絕對不行
I don't want her to either…
我也不想讓她加入
I really don't want that either,
我也不想要那樣
but if we don't let her join us, she's going to tell the truth to Nobuta.
但如果不讓她加入 她就會把真相告訴野豬
that her first friend ever was the one who'd been harassing her?
她的第一個朋友 竟然就是騷擾她的人嗎？
Nobuta could end up not believing in anything again.
野豬可能又會變得什麼都不相信
I don't believe that things will change.
我不相信事情會有所改變
When I believe and open up my heart,
我曾經相信，並敞開心房
I only get hurt.
卻只是受到傷害而已
If she crawls into her shell again,
如果她再次封閉自我
I get the feeling she may never come out again.
恐怕就再也無法敞開心房了吧
It's nice to be here.
請多多指教
Arf!
汪
I was so incredibly afraid, I couldn't stand it.
我非常害怕，內心充滿恐懼
Probably, the reason I made the wrong choice
也許就是因為這樣
was because of that.
我做出了錯誤的選擇
-Yuck. -What? Why?
-難吃 -什麼？為什麼？
You know, I still think
我還是覺得
we should make up another catchphrase or line for you.
我們應該再幫妳想別的口頭禪或台詞
Like, "The IT revolution in food!"
像是“食物界的資訊科技革命”
Yes. When you eat it…
沒錯，當妳吃下去時
"Hotdog bun!" I like that!
“熱狗麵包”，不錯啊
I know.
我知道了
"Inside my mouth, it's like the Satsuma-Choshu Alliance!"
“我的嘴裡有如薩長同盟一般”
"Satsuma-Choshu Alliance!" Yes!
“薩長同盟”，很棒啊
-Clink clink! -Try Satsuma-Choshu Alliance.
-鏘鏘 -試試看薩長同盟吧
Inside my mouth, it's like the Satsuma-Choshu Alliance.
“我的嘴裡有如薩長同盟一般”
Then do "Clink clink!"
然後說“鏘鏘”
-Hey. Excuse me. -Clink clink!
-聽我說 -鏘鏘
Let's try to be more serious.
我們認真一點吧
We are being serious.
我們是認真的啊
Seriously serious.
很認真喔
The way you do things is really pretty weak.
你們的做法太遜了
That hurts!
好痛
What do you mean by weak?
哪裡遜了？
I think this is why Kotani is still so dull.
我覺得這就是小谷 還是一樣無趣的原因
If we want her to be popular, we need to be more thorough.
如果我們想讓她受歡迎 就必須做得更徹底
I think there are still lots of things that need to be improved, like education
我認為還有很多需要改進的地方 例如精進自己
and improving her sense of style and how she talks.
提升她的時尚感和說話方式
But, you know,
不過…
if Nobuta could do everything, would that be interesting?
如果野豬什麼都做得到 還會讓人想看嗎？
I think what's interesting is
我覺得有趣的地方…
seeing awkward Nobuta trying her best to improve.
是看到笨拙的野豬努力求進步
But I think if that makes her popular, it's not real popularity.
但我認為，若她是因此受歡迎 並不算是真正有人氣
I want Kotani to become someone that everyone would approve of.
我希望小谷成為能讓大家認同的人
You say you're producing for her,
你們說是她的改造者
but you're hardly trying at all.
但你們根本就沒有用心
Oh, that ticks me off!
氣死我了
Whack! We were here first! What gives you the right to say that?
我敲，我們是前輩 妳有什麼資格說這種話？
Now, now. It's all right. Leave it be.
好，沒關係，算了
I'm angry.
我很生氣啊
I will do my best.
我會努力的
I just need to try harder.
我只要更努力就行了
I'm sorry about that.
我很抱歉
I spoke out of place.
說了一些很自以為是的話
It's okay.
沒關係
First, why not try shortening your skirt?
首先，妳要不要先把裙子改短呢？
Don't you think it's a little long?
妳不覺得有點太長了嗎？
You think so?
是嗎？
Yes.
對啊
And I think your hair would be cuter if you had it in pigtails.
還有，我覺得妳綁馬尾會更可愛
Want to try?
要試試嗎？
-Okay. -Good.
-好 -太好了
CLOSED FOR TWO OR THREE DAYS
（休業兩、三天）
Hot springs sure sound nice.
溫泉聽起來真不錯
I'd like to go.
我也想去
Hey! You're bringing a rice cooker?
等等，你連電鍋也要帶去？
You know what? Actually, I might…
你知道嗎？其實我可能…
Yes?
什麼？
I might not ever return.
我可能不會回來了
What? That hurts!
什麼？好痛
How come?
為什麼？
The proprietress of the hot spring inn I'm going to,
那間溫泉旅館的老闆娘
she's an old classmate,
是我的老同學
but her husband died young.
但她老公早就去世了
Oh, and?
然後呢？
You see,
然後啊
she said there's something she wants to ask me to do!
她說她有事要拜託我
I see. And what is it?
原來如此，她要拜託你什麼事呢？
That's the question.
這就是問題所在
What I think is
我在想…
it's become too difficult
一個柔弱女子
for a fragile woman like her to run the inn all by herself.
要獨自經營旅館太辛苦了啊
Mr. Hirayama, are you going to
大叔，你這次…
marry that woman?
要去和她結婚嗎？
Well, there is that possibility.
是有這個可能，對吧？
I guess you could say that it just might happen.
這種事也是有可能的嘛
If I don't come back,
如果我沒回來
then assume that's what happened.
你就當作成真了吧
Seriously?
真的假的？
The way you talk, Kotani, you're way too timid.
小谷，妳說話的方式太害羞了
Yes.
是
Sit up straight.
背打直
Lift your chin up.
把頭抬起來
That's right. And talk more femininely.
沒錯，說話多一點女孩子氣
I'm not sure I can.
我不確定能不能做得到
Don't worry. You can do it.
別擔心，妳可以的
What do you recommend?
你推薦什麼呢？
The sweet and sour pork.
糖醋肉
May I have one?
可以給我一點嗎？
Sure.
好啊
It's delicious.
真好吃
-Today, Kotani's so ordinary! -Thank you.
-今天的小谷好無聊 -謝謝
Maybe it's the way she talks.
也許是她說話的方式
-Maybe so. -It's her voice.
-也許吧 -是她的聲音
-She acts differently, doesn't she? -Yes.
-她的舉止都變了，對吧？ -對啊
And her skirt is shorter too.
裙子也變短了
Seriously?
-真的嗎？
Cut that out! That's so perverted!
別這樣，好變態
-You're perverted too! -I'll surprise check again tomorrow.
-你也很變態啊 -我明天會再來突擊檢查
I want to go back.
我想變回原本的模樣
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
This doesn't feel like the real me.
這感覺不像真正的我
But isn't this what producing is?
但改造不就是這回事嗎？
I mean, you're playing someone that isn't yourself.
妳要扮演一個不是自己的角色
But…
但是…
If she doesn't like it, then maybe we should stop.
如果她不喜歡，那就別這麼做吧
Why do you spoil her like that?
你為什麼要順著她？
What? What's wrong with spoiling her?
什麼？我順著她有什麼不對嗎？
It doesn't do Kotani any good.
這樣對小谷沒有好處
Are you saying it's better for her to just deal with it and endure it?
難道讓她默默忍受比較好嗎？
You see, humans can't improve unless they do that.
但不這麼做，人類是不會進步的
Actually, I don't think that's true.
我不那麼認為
forced to put up with things they don't want to.
才會變得刻薄又殘酷
I'd rather be treated kindly by others.
我還是希望被人溫柔對待
That's why I want to be as kind as I can to people from now on.
所以我打算從現在開始 盡可能溫柔對待別人
You want to be treated kindly?
被溫柔對待？
The way you talk, you sound like a child.
你說這些話，真像是小孩子
So what if I do?
是又怎麼樣？
I'm just a brat anyway.
反正我就是個臭小鬼
The next photo could be of them kissing.
下一張可能是他們接吻的照片呢
Maybe.
也許吧
You did see the photo of Kotani hugging Kiritani, didn't you?
你有看到小谷跟桐谷擁抱的照片吧？
Then why are you still hanging around them?
你為何還跟他們混在一起？
Isn't it painful?
很痛苦吧？
To me, Shuji and Nobuta are the most important.
對我來說，修二和野豬是最重要的
I'm number two.
我自己只排名第二
You're such a liar.
你真會說謊
Everyone believes they're the most important.
每個人都認為自己最重要
I'm not lying.
我沒有說謊
It's more important to have fun every day.
我覺得每天開心比較重要
So I put my priority on that.
所以我很重視這一點
You know, don't you think your way of doing things is wrong?
妳不覺得妳這麼做不對嗎？
People shouldn't be tested.
人不該被試探
If you don't test them, then what do you do with them?
如果不試探，還能做什麼？
You cultivate them.
培養感情
With love!
用愛灌溉
Bye.
再見
UGLY PIG
（醜豬）
Kotani…
小谷
This was left on my desk.
這個在我的桌上
Thank you.
謝謝
Can I see your grandpa?
我能見見妳爺爺嗎？
The old man at the aquarium that I helped…
我在水族館幫忙的那個老爺爺
Your grandfather…
就是妳的爺爺
I want to ask him something.
我有事要問他
Can I see him?
我能見他嗎？
No.
不
You can't.
不行
Because that's a lie that I made up.
因為那是我編出來的謊言
Did you
是妳…
do those things?
做了這些事？
Did you wreck
是不是妳…
the haunted house?
破壞了鬼屋？
Did you wreck the tape?
是妳把錄影帶毀掉的嗎？
Did you do all of it?
全都是妳做的嗎？
Yes.
對
That's right.
沒錯
Why?
為什麼？
Because I hate you.
因為我討厭妳
You're irritating.
妳讓我很不爽
"The three of us are all friends."
說什麼“我們三個是朋友”
That stuff is such bullshit.
根本沒那種事
Your kindness to me
妳對我這麼好
and when you said
所以妳說…
we were friends.
我們是朋友
Those were all lies?
全都是謊言？
Yes. They're lies.
對，都是謊言
I was going to be even kinder
我本來想要跟妳變得更親近
and then push you into despair when it would be most effective.
然後在最致命的時候 把妳推進絕望深淵
Too bad, right?
真可惜，對吧？
Hey, that's enough of that.
夠了吧
She's crying.
她都哭了
Aren't you the girl Kiritani dumped?
妳不是被桐谷甩了的那個女生嗎？
I've got some news for you.
我有件事要跟妳說
Actually, Kiritani and this girl are dating.
其實桐谷正在跟這個女生交往
What? No, we're not.
什麼？我們沒有交往
So?
所以呢？
What about it?
怎麼了嗎？
Don't act so tough.
別逞強了
Was that girl your friend?
剛才那個人是妳的朋友嗎？
Roast chestnuts.
炒栗子
Nice and warm, right?
很溫暖吧？
Would you rather you were still friends even if she kept lying to you?
如果她一直騙妳 妳還願意繼續跟她當朋友？
I'm also glad I learned the truth.
我也很慶幸能知道真相
It feels lonely being lied to.
被騙的感覺很寂寞吧
But
但是…
it's also probably lonely if you're always lying.
一直說謊的話，可能也會很寂寞
I wanted everyone
我希望每個人
to think that I had a girlfriend.
都認為我有女朋友
Sorry.
抱歉
You may be right.
也許吧
You like it?
好吃嗎？
-Mr. Yokoyama! -Yes?
-橫山老師 -是？
The end-of-year party last night sure was rough, wasn't it?
你昨晚在尾牙餐會真是不簡單啊
The end-of-year party? What happened back then?
尾牙餐會？發生了什麼事？
What?
什麼？
After all you did, you don't remember it?
你不記得自己做了什麼事？
What? Did I do something?
什麼？我做了什麼嗎？
-If you don't remember, forget it! -What? Wait!
-如果不記得就算了 -什麼？等等
Tell me what happened!
告訴我是什麼事
-Mr. Yokoyama, you sure are young! -What the heck happened?
-橫山老師，你真青春啊 -到底發生什麼事？
-You got drunk and dissed the principal. -No way!
-你喝醉酒辱罵校長 -不會吧？
What's more, you slapped your resignation in his face.
還把辭呈甩在他臉上
Resignation?
辭呈？
You smacked it right on his forehead.
你用辭呈打他的額頭
I don't remember that.
我不記得了
I have officially accepted this resignation.
我批准你的辭呈了
You're kidding!
不會吧
No, I'm not.
是真的
Today, we're surprise checking first year, class B.
今天我們要來突擊1年B班
Hello.
你好
You know, Kotani is the best to do this show.
還是小谷最適合主持這個節目
Yes. This isn't funny.
對啊，現在完全不好笑
Yes, not at all. It's dull.
對，一點都不好笑，真無趣
Not at all.
無聊死了
Kusano.
草野
Where's Kotani?
小谷呢？
She's absent.
她沒來
That figures.
果然啊
Her friend said awful things to her yesterday.
她朋友昨天對她說了很過分的話
They're both good? Today…
兩個都好吃？今天…
Friend? You mean her?
朋友？妳說她嗎？
Yes. That girl.
對，就是那女孩
Aoi told Nobuta the truth?
蒼井告訴野豬真相了？
That girl… Darn her.
那女的真討厭
The stuff she said was pretty harsh.
她說的話非常過分
I just wanted to tell you that.
我只是想告訴你們這件事
Yip yip.
嗷嗷
Mariko!
真理子
Thank you.
謝謝
Kotani will be all right.
小谷會沒事的
It may take time, but she'll be okay.
可能會需要點時間，但她會沒事的
Accepting the truth is really painful.
接受事實是一件很痛苦的事
But…
但是…
it's not impossible to do.
並不是做不到的事
Since we're friends, I'll have it for free.
既然是朋友，那我就收下了
Okay?
可以嗎？
Thank you. I'll take good care of it.
謝謝妳，我會好好保管的
Nobuta!
野豬
Kotani!
小谷
Kotani?
小谷？
I know you're in there, Nobuta.
我知道妳在裡面，野豬
-Nobuta! -Yip yip! This is when you use it! Yip!
-野豬 -嗷嗷，你應該學我，嗷
I knew this would happen.
我就知道會這樣
There are some things you just can't ignore.
有些事情是無法避免的
-Nobuta!
-野豬
Come out!
快出來
-Kotani! -Nobuta!
-小谷 -野豬
I know you're there!
我知道妳在裡面
Nobuta!
野豬
We are…
我們是…
-Sumidagawa High Night Angels!
-隅田川高中夜天使
Come on! Put Kotani back on, man!
快點讓小谷回去主持吧
-We want to see Kotani's, "Yuck!" -That's right!
-我們想看小谷的“難吃” -沒錯
And when it's really bad, her eyebrows twitch.
如果真的超難吃，她的眉毛會抽動
-That's right! -I want to see that twitch again!
-好想再看一次那個抽動
-It's a lucky day when you see that. -Yes! That's lucky!
-如果有看到，代表那天很幸運 -對啊，很幸運
Get the camera!
去拿攝影機
Let's film this and give it to Nobuta.
拍下來給野豬看吧
Yip!
嗷
I have a favor to ask everyone.
我想請大家幫個忙
I'm afraid Kotani
我覺得小谷…
might not ever come back to school.
可能再也不會回學校了
But if she hears what you're saying
但如果她聽到你們說的話
I think she'll come back.
或許她會願意回來
That's the kind of person she is.
她就是這樣的人
So I want to film all of your comments and bring them to Kotani.
所以我想拍下你們想說的話 然後拿給小谷看
Will you do that?
可以嗎？
I know none of you want to do a favor for me.
我知道你們不會想幫忙我
But just this once…
但這一次…
do me this favor.
幫我這個忙，好嗎？
Please.
拜託大家了
When I think about…
當我想到…
how you may not even be…
你們可能
listening to what I say right now,
根本沒在聽我現在說的話
I'm afraid.
我就感到很害怕
I'm so afraid, I could die.
我害怕到快死了
We're listening.
我們有在聽
Don't worry. We hear you.
別擔心，我們能理解
Yes.
對啊
I'm not sure what happened,
我不確定發生了什麼事
but let's help out.
但還是會幫忙吧
-Yes. -Right?
-對 -對吧？
-It's to bring Kotani back. -That's right!
-為了讓小谷回來 -沒錯
Okay!
好
Get the camera ready!
攝影機準備好
-All right!
-好
All right!
來囉
It's the great first episode of "Kotani Surprise Lunch Check"!
這是“小谷的午餐突襲” 精彩的第一集
TO NOBUTA
（給野豬）
OINK
（噗）
Here it comes! Here comes "Yuck!"
要來了，要講“難吃”了
-Yuck. -There it is!
-難吃 -她說了
-Nice! -I just love Kotani's "Yuck!"
-帥啦 -我最喜歡小谷說“難吃”
Please! Let's see that twitching eyebrow of yours!
拜託，讓我們看妳抽動的眉毛
Please do an episode on my love-filled bento lunch.
請來拍我的愛心便當
-Please!
-拜託了
-The best break from studies is… -Yuck!
-讀書休息時的最佳良伴 -難吃
Isn't it obvious?
這是一定要的啦
-Kotani! -Come back soon!
-小谷 -快點回來
I want to see your "Yuck!"
我想聽妳說“難吃”
-Yuck!
-難吃
Yuck!
難吃
Try some "Honey Honey."
來喝喝看“蜂蜜蜂蜜”吧
Kotani's way better than Aoi.
小谷比蒼井好太多了
-Replace her!
-把她換掉
Bring back Kotani, damn it!
讓小谷回來主持，找死啊
-Kotani!
-小谷
Thumbs up, everyone.
大家豎起大拇指
-Right!
-好
Nobuta, come back!
野豬，快回來
Yes! Reporter Kotani! We've been waiting for you!
好耶，小谷記者，我們都在等妳
Welcome back!
歡迎回來
-L-O-V-E! Lovely Kotani!
-L、O、V、E，可愛的小谷
That girl's probably going to do something again.
那女孩可能又要惹事了
I think she's frightened.
我覺得她很害怕
Why?
-為什麼？ -她怕我們把真相告訴大家
I think that scares her.
那讓她很害怕
Then we shouldn't worry.
那我們就不用擔心了
But if she feels cornered,
但如果她覺得走投無路…
I just hope she doesn't go into a frenzy.
我只希望她不會做出什麼瘋狂的事
I don't really get her, but she's a real pain.
雖然不知道她想做什麼 但她真讓人頭痛
"Come to the school roof."
“來學校屋頂
"Aoi…"
蒼井”
So you came.
妳來啦
What is it?
有什麼事？
If I jump from here, do you think I'll die?
如果我從這裡跳下去 妳覺得我會死嗎？
Are you angry?
妳生氣了嗎？
Of course, you are.
我想也是
I did do some pretty cruel things to you.
我確實對妳做了很過分的事
Will you forgive me for what I did?
妳能原諒我嗎？
If you won't forgive me, I'll jump from here.
妳不原諒我的話，我就跳下去
How about it?
怎麼樣？
Will you forgive me or not?
妳到底肯不肯原諒我？
I can't forgive you.
我無法原諒妳
Okay.
我知道了
Then I'll jump.
那我就跳下去
Stay back!
別過來
This is your final chance.
這是妳最後的機會
Will you
妳願意…
forgive me?
原諒我嗎？
Kotani,
小谷
will you?
妳願意嗎？
What are you doing?
妳們在做什麼？
Aoi wants me to forgive her.
蒼井要我原諒她
If I don't, she says she'll jump.
如果不原諒她，她就要跳下去
What will it be?
所以呢？
Will you forgive me or not?
妳到底肯不肯原諒我？
I told you to quit testing people.
我說過不要這樣試探別人
This is the only way she knows how to act.
這是她唯一知道的生存之道
You know everything, don't you, Kiritani?
你覺得自己無所不知，對吧，桐谷？
You're amazing.
真厲害啊
Don't jump.
別跳
Then you forgive me?
那妳會原諒我嗎？
No, I can't forgive you.
我不能原諒妳
But don't jump.
但妳別跳下去
It doesn't work that way.
規則不是這樣的
It's one or the other.
只能選其中一條路
Wait!
等等
You…
妳…
You don't even really want her to forgive you, do you?
妳根本就不希望她原諒妳，對吧？
That's right.
沒錯
I don't care if she forgives me.
我才不管她會不會原諒我
Then what is it that you want to do?
那妳到底想做什麼？
I want you to remember me.
我要你們記得我
Even if it's for awful things,
就算是令人討厭的事情
I want you to remember…
我也要你們記得
that I existed.
我存在過
That's all.
就這樣
Bye.
再見
Aoi!
蒼井
That hurts!
好痛
I just had a weird dream.
我剛剛做了一個奇怪的夢
A dream that Aoi jumped?
蒼井跳樓的夢？
It was the school roof!
在學校的屋頂
That hurts!
好痛
Aoi.
蒼井
Aoi?
蒼井？
Did you dream that
妳是不是夢見
you jumped from the roof?
妳從屋頂跳下去？
Thank goodness.
太好了
I'm so glad
妳還活著
you're alive.
真是太好了
DELPHINE
（戴菲尼）
What are you doing?
你在這裡做什麼？
I'm just waiting for someone.
我在等人
At a place like this?
在這種地方等人？
Who are you waiting for?
你在等誰？
Someone called my phone out of the blue and said,
有人突然打來跟我說
"Let's be friends."
“我們當朋友吧”
And
然後…
you went to wait for them?
你就來這裡等對方？
Yes.
對啊
But they haven't shown up.
可是一直都沒有人來
You must have been tricked.
你是被騙了吧？
Maybe so.
也許吧
They sounded awfully lonely though.
不過，對方的聲音聽起來很寂寞
they're here!
來了
Are you the one who called me?
是你打給我的嗎？
What a magnificent moon.
好漂亮的月亮
Yes.
是啊
Why the four of us had the same dream,
為什麼我們四個會做同樣的夢
I still don't know.
我還是不知道原因
You let me join your group,
雖然你們讓我加入了你們
but it wasn't as fun as I expected.
但並不如我預期的有趣
I'll release you.
我要退出
Aoi disappeared from us forever.
蒼井從我們身邊消失了
My classmates started talking to me again.
同學們又開始跟我說話了
Shuji.
修二…
Yokoyama gave his resignation to the principal and has to quit.
橫山老師向校長遞了辭呈 所以不得不辭職了
What? Yokoyama's quitting?
什麼？橫山老師要辭職？
For Yokoyama's sake, we stayed up all night forging petitions.
為了橫山老師 我們徹夜沒睡，偽造請願書
I LOVE MR. YOKOYAMA! AKIKO KUSAKA
（我最喜歡橫山老師了，日下希子）
Yip!
嗷
Everyone, we got 100 petitions!
各位，我們寫了一百封請願書
Out of consideration of these petitions, I'll forget it.
看在這些請願書的份上 這次的事就算了
Thank you!
謝謝
Mr. Hirayama came back too.
大叔也回來了
So that proprietress wanted to ask you
所以那位老闆娘要拜託你…
to buy health products?
買健康食品嗎？
Yes. That's right.
對，沒錯
Oh, I see.
這樣啊
What are you looking at?
妳在看什麼？
Have you ever been in a situation that was beyond redemption?
老師有遇過無法挽回的情況嗎？
Yes.
有啊
I have.
我有
Did you make it through alone?
妳獨自撐過去了？
No. With friends.
不是，是靠朋友
Is that right?
是嗎？
My friends brought me through.
我朋友陪著我熬過去的
Only people
只有人類
can save other people.
可以拯救彼此
I think I'm going to start over.
我想要重新開始
Start what over?
重新開始什麼？
In our class,
在班上…
I think I'll start building Shuji Kiritani again.
我要重新塑造一個桐谷修二
You want to become popular again?
你想再次成為受歡迎的人嗎？
I wouldn't be so sure about that.
這我就不確定了
I'll be your producer. Twang!
我願意當你的改造者，叮
No, thank you. Twang!
不用，謝謝，叮
Twang! Why?
叮，為什麼？
As long as you have someone,
只要身邊有朋友
even if you're in a situation beyond redemption,
就算陷入萬劫不復的境地
you can make it through.
仍然可以撐過去
Welcome home.
回來啦
Yes…
對…
What's your problem?
你是怎麼了？
This is kind of sudden, but I'm getting transferred.
事情發生得很突然，我被調職了
What? We're moving?
什麼？我們要搬家？
Yes.
對
That tickles!
好癢…
As long as I'm here,
只要在這裡
I doubt that I'll ever lose my way.
我就不會迷失方向吧
Nobuta! Hold him!
野豬，抓住他
FINAL EPISODE PREVIEW FAREWELL AMIGO
（最終回預告）
Farewell,
再會
Shuji Kiritani.
桐谷修二
THIS DRAMA IS A WORK OF FICTION
（本劇純屬虛構）
Subtitle translation by: Brian Athey
字幕翻譯：黃雅婷